[
  {
    "question": "Core of Linux operating system is _____",
    "a": "Shell",
    "b": "Terminal",
    "c": "Kernel",
    "d": "Command",
    "answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Command you use to create Linux file system is _____",
    "a": "fsck",
    "b": "mkfs",
    "c": "mount",
    "d": "None of the above",
    "answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following directory contains configuration files in Linux?",
    "a": "/etc/",
    "b": "/dev/",
    "c": "/root/",
    "d": "/bin/",
    "answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "____ is sponsored by Red Hat.",
    "a": "Fedora Linux",
    "b": "SuSE Linux",
    "c": "Lycoris Linux",
    "d": "Xandros Linux",
    "answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which command is used to remove files?",
    "a": "delete",
    "b": "erase",
    "c": "dm",
    "d": "rm",
    "answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "____ command is used to remove directory.",
    "a": "rdir",
    "b": "rd",
    "c": "rmdir",
    "d": "None of the above",
    "answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many primary partitions can exist on one drive?",
    "a": "16",
    "b": "4",
    "c": "2",
    "d": "1",
    "answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "FSF stands for ___________",
    "a": "First Serve First",
    "b": "Free Software File",
    "c": "Free Software Foundation",
    "d": "None of the above",
    "answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "mv command can be used for ",
    "a": "Renaming a file",
    "b": "Move as well as rename the file",
    "c": "Move the file",
    "d": "None of the above",
    "answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following combination of keys is used to exit the terminal?",
    "a": "Ctrl + z",
    "b": "Ctrl + t",
    "c": "Ctrl + d",
    "d": "Ctrl + e",
    "answer": "c"
  }
]
